<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-02T10:00:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Engineering by Trade</title><subtitle>A blog aimed at anyone interested in software development</subtitle><author><name>EBT</name><email>engineeringbytrade@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/02/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2020-09-02T08:51:35-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T08:51:35-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/02/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/02/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>EBT</name><email>engineeringbytrade@gmail.com</email></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Pursue a Career in Programming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/2020/09/01/why-pursue-a-career-in-programming.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Pursue a Career in Programming" /><published>2020-09-01T16:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T16:01:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/2020/09/01/why-pursue-a-career-in-programming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/2020/09/01/why-pursue-a-career-in-programming.html">&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the single greatest thing about the tech industry is that anybody can excel. It is a gatekeeper-less realm in which hard work and productivity can outcome anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this? If you want to be a physician, you have to go to 8+ years of med school, graduate with an MD or DO, complete residency, and then finally you are underway. If you want to be a lawyer, you must graduate Law School and pass the bar. These professions have this for good reason – you want someone you can trust when dealing with sensitive issues having a minuscule margin of error, often times determining life or death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, software development can and often does share the same requirement of perfection. Think about Tesla, who takes on the burden of rider safety daily in their autonomous vehicles. An error in a program running the next NASA space shuttle could spell catastrophe. Even today’s banking infrastructure is high risk software that requires a meticulous attention to detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However there is often a need for development in less precise fields. Facebook started as what amounts to an online phonebook for a university. Google simply tried to parse the proverbial haystack of online content in an easily searchable manner. These are now extremely successful businesses, but started with a simple idea and held tightly the value of “pulling yourself up by your bootstraps”. Mark Zuckerberg himself dropped out of undergrad. What mattered is that they had an idea, and they worked hard to pursue it. This mindset has led to an industry that is much more open to people and vastly more willing to look at their bodies of work rather than degrees on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about what this means. This means a 16 year old can get a job at a top firm if they put the work in. This is freedom. This is what a development career can offer. It doesn’t matter who you are or what your past career or life has entailed. Learning how to code can be a great equalizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An indirect benefit of this is that there is a strong and supportive community in the software development world. Think about Stack Overflow, where thousands of developers ask and answer questions in an open space. Open Source Culture means that software engineering thrives off of shared knowledge and allowing others access to the code they’ve written. This in turn provides an extremely robust resource bank for any programming language, all free for you to utilize and learn from. This is obviously an oversimplification of the Open Source industry, but try to find this level of information for free in any other industry and you’d likely return empty-handed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, learning to be a developer has extremely low friction when thinking of the resources available. Stack Overflow, YouTube, and the like are a treasure trove of valuable information to help you advance in the topic. Not only that, but you don’t need to invest in a four year degree. You don’t even need to pay for a bootcamp if you’re driven enough to learn and build projects on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why software engineering? Because the only blocker is you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>EBT</name><email>engineeringbytrade@gmail.com</email></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html">In my opinion, the single greatest thing about the tech industry is that anybody can excel. It is a gatekeeper-less realm in which hard work and productivity can outcome anything else.</summary></entry></feed>